我和姐妹们都记得...
My sisters and I remember that winter...
童年里最冷的一年冬天
as the coldest of our childhood.
几年前我们家就遭遇了暂时性的经济拮据
A temporary poverty had settled upon our family some years before.
（康柯德市 马萨诸塞州）
内战导致燃料和灯油短缺
The war had made fuel and lamp oil scarce.
但是外在的需求总能孕育出内在的创造力
But necessity is indeed the mother of invention.
因此就在这么个黑暗时期...我们家 马屈家
Somehow in that dark time...our family, the March family,
不知不觉创造了属于自己的光明
seemed to create its own light.
妈咪！妈咪到家了！
Marmee! Marmee's home!
妈咪!妈咪!妈咪!
Marmee! Marmee!Marmee!
我们等了又等！
We waited and waited!
我们“期等”你几个钟头了
We've been "expectorating" you for hours!
有吗 亲爱的？
Have you, my darling?
该说“期待” 你个草包
" Expecting," featherhead.
噢 妈咪 你都快冻坏了！
Oh, Marmee, you're frozen!
是的
Yes.
你如果看到这个冷天里 在希望之家外面排队的人就知道了
If you could see the people lined up outside Hope House in this bitter cold.
唔 你的脸颊特别暖和
Mmm, your cheeks are so warm.
谢谢 小蟋蟀
Thank you, cricket.
你做好圣诞济贫小包了吗？
Have you finished your Christmas bundles?
-今年做了好多! 我们还送了… -哦 你的感冒怎么样了？
-So many this year! We were handing out… - Oh, how was your cold?
-好多了 -那就好
- Better. -That's good.
我们送食物的速度...就跟做篮子的速度一样快
We were handing out food...as quickly as we could make up the baskets.
艾米小姐 知道我口袋里有什么吗？
Now, Miss Amy, what is this in my pocket?
是爸爸的信！
Father!
“我最亲爱的家人
" My dearest family,
我目前安然无恙
I am well and safe.
我们驻札在‘波特莫克’”
Our battalion is encamped on the 'Potamac'."
是“波特摩克”
Potomac.
“对远离家乡的我们而言 十二月是个寒冷的季节
" December makes a hard, cold season for all of us so far from home.
我日夜思念着我的女儿们…
I think of my girls day and night...
对你们的爱是我最好的慰藉
and find my best comfort in your affection.
我祈祷你们的艰困不至于大到无法承受
I pray that your own hardships will not be too great to bear.
给她们我的爱和我的吻
Give them all my dear love and a kiss.
告诉她们我白天思念她们
Tell them I think of them by day,
晚上为她们祈祷
pray for them by night."
可怜的父亲
Poor Father.
我真是个自私的女孩
I'm a selfish girl.
哦！小不点
Oh! Little ones.
这是圣诞夜 爸爸不会希望我们难过的
It's Christmas Eve. Father wouldn't want us to be sad now.
叮叮当 在天堂的高处
♪ Ding-dong merrily on high ♪
钟声快乐的响起
♪ In heaven the bells are ringing ♪
叮叮当 天空裂开了
♪ Ding-dong merrily the sky is riven ♪
天使快乐的歌唱
♪ with angels singing ♪
荣耀颂歌
♪ Glor-o-o-ria ♪
欢呼之声响彻云霄
♪ Hosanna in excelsis ♪
该睡觉了 艾米小姐
To bed, Miss Amy.
圣诞快乐 甜心
Merry Christmas, sweetheart.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
让教堂钟声绵延不绝
♪ Let steeple bells be swungen. And i-o i-o i-o ♪
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
荣耀颂歌
♪ Glor-o-o-ria ♪
圣诞快乐 贝丝
Merry Christmas, Beth.
-我爱你 -我爱你
- Love you. - I love you.
欢呼之声响彻云霄
♪ Hosanna in excelsis ♪
我的乔 圣诞快乐
My Jo.Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐 妈咪
Merry Christmas, Marmee.
欢呼之声响彻云霄
♪ Hosanna in excelsis ♪
别睡得太晚
And don't sit up too late.
我不会的
I won't.
用优美的节奏祝福你
♪ May you beautifully rhyme ♪
歌手们欢快的歌
♪ your eve-time song ye singers ♪
一到深夜 我的思绪就会
Late at night, my mind would come alive
随着脑中的声音 故事和...朋友一起活跃起来
with voices and stories...and friends
它们对我来说就如同这个真实的世界一般珍贵
as dear to me as any in the real world.
我沉浸于此 渴望着改变我的生活
I gave myself up to it, longing for transformation.
哦 多神奇的食物！
Oh, what miraculous food!
跟往常一样不是吗 汉娜？
Isn't this just like the old days, Hannah?
我们不能吃 我们只能看着它
We shouldn't eat it. We should just look at it.
我正要吃它呢
I'm going to eat it.
乔？乔 下来了！
Jo? Jo, come down!
我醒了！可怕的钢琴声
I'm awake! Horrible piano.
汉娜完成了一个圣诞奇迹
Hannah's put together an absolute Christmas miracle.
那是香肠吗？
Is that sausage?
等等！
Wait!
奶油
Butter
哦, 奶油!哦 哦 这就是奶油的“神性”吗？
Oh, butter! Oh, oh, isn't butter "divinity"?
哦 主 感谢你赐予这顿早餐
Oh, God, thank you for this breakfast.
乔 小天使 去叫你妈咪
Jo, angel, fetch your Marmee.
她天没亮就去见那几个德国人了
She went out at the crack of dawn to see some Germans.
是汉默家 他家的那个男孩一句英文都不会说
Hummel, the boy said not a word of English.
他爸爸去世了
His da's gone.
已经有六个孩子 他的妈妈又要生了
Six children, and she's 'bout to issue another.
可以送些柴火过去 我敢肯定他们没有柴火
May as well take 'em a stick of firewood. Sure they haven't got any.
甚至早餐都没有
Or breakfast either.
也许我们可以把我们的面包送给汉默他们
Perhaps we could send the Hummels our bread.
奶油也一并送去吧 奶油用不着了...因为没有面包来涂
Might as well send the butter too. Butter's not much use...without bread to put it on.
哦 好美的雪！
Oh, wonderful snow!
你是不是想像狗一样在雪上打滚呢？
Don't you wish you could roll about in it like dogs?
她们曾是我们这最美满的家庭之一
Once one of our finest families.
真是野餐的好天气！
Lovely weather for a picnic!
走吧 西奥多 我们上教堂要迟到了
Come along, Theodore. We'll be late for church.
乔 你该让他们先开口 不然他们会怎么看我们？
Jo, you should let them speak first. What will they think of us?
噢 别回头！
Oh, don't look back!
我们在嫩绿的树林间举杯同欢
Here we come a-wassailing among the leaves so green
我们在如此美好的天气四处游荡
And here we come a-wandering so fair as to be seen
愿爱与喜悦降临你
Love and joy come to you
也降临你的酒宴
And to you your wassail too
上帝祝福你并给你一个快乐的新年
And God bless you and send you a happy new year
并给你一个快乐的新年
And God send you a happy new year
骑士与女士 精灵与僮仆
Knights and ladies, elves and pages,
僧侣与花童...
monks and flower girls...
都快乐的一同跳舞
all mingled gaily in the dance.
波琳看见新郎的面罩掉了下来 吓得大叫起来...
Pauline cried out in horror as her bridegroom's mask fell...
那人并非她的爱人佛迪南...
disclosing not her lover Ferdinand...
却是他的死敌 安东尼伯爵
but the face of his sworn enemy, Count Antonio.
他言道 我要复仇
Revenge is mine, quoth he.
后情发展 请看续集
Continued in the following edition.
精彩的段落 史诺戈斯先生
Excellent installment, Mr. Snodgrass.
噢 我喜欢禁忌式的婚姻
Oh, I love forbidden marriages!
You ought to publish it, Jo. Really! Not just in the Pickwick Portfolio.
你应该出版它 乔 真的！而不是只登在我们的皮威克报上
（皮威克报，原著中乔自办的家庭报纸）
塔普曼先生 你是在贬低我们这么好的报刊吗？
Mr. Tupman, are you demeaning our fine newspaper?
“小长春... ”这是广告
"One periwink..." Advertisement.
“一条属于小长春先生的小长春花腰带...
"One periwinkle sash belonging to Mr. N. Winkle...
被人由洗衣店取走...
has been 'abscondated' from the wash line...
小长春先生寻求消息协助 以便寻回失物"
which gentleman desires any reports leading to its recovery."
出版社的先生们 听着 听着！请关注...
Gentlemen of the press, hear, hear! I call to your attention...
我们塔曼先生的“饮料史”
our Mr. Tupman's The History of the Squash.
哦 别念我写的故事
Oh, don't read mine.
贝丝 你这不是故事 这就是个食谱
Beth, this isn't a story. It's a recipe.
噢 亲爱的 我一直都不知道该写什么
Oh, dear, I never know what to write.
写作的首要原则 塔普曼先生
First rule of writing, Mr. Tupman,
不要写你了解的事
is never write what you know.
我们觉得那男孩如何？
What do we think of the boy?
他像不像《尼古拉斯·尼克贝》里的斯密？
（《尼古拉斯·尼克贝》，狄更斯小说）
Is he a captive like Smee in Nicholas Nickleby?
他看起来很孤单
He looks lonely.
你想他会不会来访？
You don't think he'll try to call?
也许他有啥秘密...
Maybe he has a secret...
悲剧的 欧洲式的秘密
tragic, European secret.
他们说 他根本没有受过教育 他在意大利的艺术家和流浪汉中长大
He's had no upbringing at all, they say. He was reared in Italy among artists and vagrants.
他不是有个看着特高贵的额头吗？
Doesn't he have a noble brow?
如果我是个男孩子 我就想长成那样
If I were a boy, I'd want to look just like that.
想想看 放弃我书里的意大利 却和那糟老头住的感觉！
Imagine giving up Italy to come live with that awful old man!
乔 别说“糟老头” 那是粗话
Jo, please don't say awful. It's slang.
和他住我一定会吓坏
I'd be terrified to live with him.
我倒不介意住这么大房子 还有这么好的东西
I shouldn't mind living in such a fine house and having nice things.
喔 没有礼物就不像圣诞节
Oh, it doesn't seen like Christmas this year without presents.
我十分渴望拥有画笔
I'm desperate for drawing pencils.
我希望不必为马屈姑婆...那个乖戾的守财奴工作
I wish I didn't have to work for Great-Aunt March...that crabby old miser.
你呢 贝丝？你的圣诞愿望是什么？
And you, Beth. What's your Christmas wish?
我想要战争结束 这样爸爸就能回家了
I'd like the war to end so Father can come home.
哦 好贝丝
Oh, sweet Beth.
我们都想要这样
We all want that.
他们家有一架漂亮的钢琴
They do have a beautiful piano.
等我成为作家 我就给你买架上帝创世以来最好的钢琴
Wait 'til I'm a writer. I'll buy you the best piano in creation.
如果她没给你买 你可以来我这弹我的
And if she doesn't, you can come over and play mine.
当我结婚时 我要变得非常富有
When I marry, I'm going to be disgustingly rich.
那如果你爱的男人是个穷人但人很好 就像爸爸一样呢？
And what if the man you love is a poor man but good, like Father?
这个嘛 爱不像长着一个难看的鼻子那样别无选择
Well, it isn't like being stuck with the dreadful nose you get.
一个人可以选择要爱谁
One does have a choice to whom one loves.
你的鼻子天生就很可爱！
You have a lovely nose!
我不会为钱而结婚
I wouldn't marry for the money.
我的意思是 万一他事业失败呢？
I mean, what if his business goes bust?
并且 在鹰报 他们给每则刊登的故事支付五美元
Besides, down at the Eagle, they pay $5 for each story they print.
这个嘛 现在我脑中就有十个故事！
Well, I have ten stories in my head right now!
各位先生
Gentlemen,
我不爱谈钱
I dislike all this money talk.
这不高雅
It isn't refined.
如果不注意个人财务是高雅的标志...
If lack of attention to personal finances is a mark of refinement...
那我敢说我们马屈家是这里最高贵的家庭了
then I'd say the Marches are the most elegant family in Concord.
我们都会长大的 梅格
We'll all grow up someday, Meg.
我们该想清楚自己要什么
We might as well know what we want.
可以了
That'll do.
把马车拉开 动作麻利点
Put the carriage away, and look smart about it.
好的 先生
Very good, sir.
圣诞快乐！
Merry Christmas!
我对今晚的感觉很棒
I have the most wonderful feeling about tonight.
梅格和乔 你们得告诉我...所有关于贝尔·嘉丁纳的“精致”事
Meg and Jo, you have to tell me..."exquisitely" everything about Belle Gardiner.
她鼻子和她的戒指长啥样 安妮·嘉丁纳说她的戒指是颗祖母绿
What her nose looks like and about her ring. Annie Gardiner says it's an emerald.
你能想象吗？除了我 大家都很幸运
Can you imagine? Everyone's lucky but me.
真高兴我不必去 不用和那些可怕的人一起...
I'm glad I don't have to go and be with those frightening people...
也不用试着找话来聊
and try to think of things to say.
嘘
Hush now.
噢 注意点 乔...
Oh, mind you, Jo...
晚餐别吃太多...还有不要和人握手 没别的了
don't eat much at supper... and don't shake hands with people. It isn't the thing anymore.
乔 你的裙子！
Jo, your dress!
噢 我知道！
Oh, I know!
你老是站的离炉火太近
You always stand too close to the fire.
噢 亲爱的 这个 只要背靠着墙别让人看见就行
Oh, dear. Well, just keep your backside to the wall.
梅格 看 多可爱的小鞋跟
Meg, look. What cunning little heels.
它们太小了
They're rather small.
没关系 只穿一晚而已
That's all right. It's only for one night.
你觉得会有人注意到...它们是拿碎布袋做的吗？
You don't suppose anyone will notice... they came out of the rag bag, do you?
啊...呃 你必须得有鞋跟
Uh-uh. You have to have heels.
这是什么怪味道？
What's that strange smell?
像是烧焦的羽毛
Like burnt feathers.
天啊！
Heavens above!
你毁了我！
You've ruined me!
对不起！对不起 你就不该让我弄头发！
I'm sorry! I'm sorry. You shouldn't have had me do it!
-你把一切都毁了 –梅格 别担心 很快会长回来的
-You spoil everything. -Meg, don't worry. It'll come out soon.
我不能就这样出去！
I can't go out like this!
好吧！那我也不去了
Good! I'm not going either.
来 我们把蝴蝶结放前面
Here, we'll place my bow in front.
好极了 遮住了
Yes, that covers it.
它很配呀
It's very becoming.
我再也不会有追求者们了
I'll never have any suitors.
我会变成一个风干的老姑娘
I'll just be a dried-up old spinster.
你不需要许多的追求者 你只需要一个
You don't need scores of suitors. You only need one,
前提是他就是那个对的人
if he's the right one.
听听这孩子说的
Listen to the child.
梅格不打算马上结婚 对吧？
Meg isn't going to be married right away, is she?
有了乔的帮忙 我再也嫁不出去了
With Jo's help, I never will.
你一定非常快乐
You must be so happy.
哦 贝尔 你真迷人
Oh, Belle, it's enchanting.
这个 我最好去帮一下我妈 原谅我
Well, I best go help Mama. Excuse me.
天呀！对不起
Jehoshaphat! I'm sorry.
不 不 留下！
No, no, stay!
这是个不错的藏匿处
It's not a bad hiding place.
你看 我不认识任何人...所以我觉得站在那盯着人看好尴尬
You see, I don't know anyone... so I feel awkward standing and staring at people.
我应该穿上我的外套吗？我不懂这些规矩
Should I put on my jacket? I never know the rules.
呃 嗯 我是罗利
Um, um, I'm Laurie.
西奥多·罗伦斯 不过
Theodore Laurence, but
我是 呃 大家都叫我罗利
I'm, uh, I'm called Laurie.
乔.马屈 嗯...
Jo March. Um...
那 你在盯着谁看？
So, who were you staring at?
呃 其实 是你 你在玩什么游戏吗？
Uh, you, actually. What... what game were you playing?
我不知道 不过我想我赢了
I don't know, but I think I won.
你还盯着谁在看？
Who else?
这个 我对...
Well, I was...
我对那个人很感兴趣
I was quite taken with that one.
那是梅格
That's Meg.
那是我姐姐
That's my sister.
她的前额全都秃了
She's completely bald in front.
是真的吗 你和艺术家，游民一起生活在意大利？
Is it true that you lived in Italy among artists and vagrants?
我母亲是意大利人
My mother was Italian.
一个 呃 钢琴家
A, uh, pianist.
但爷爷不喜欢她
Grandfather disapproved of her.
真的？我看过类似的剧本 你喜欢戏剧吗？
Truly? I saw a play like that once. Do you like the theater?
哦 是的
Oh, yes.
你在那里出生的吗？
Were you born there?
那里？在...
Where? In...
在 呃 意大利
In, uh, Italy.
-你会说法文还是意大利文？ -在家说英语
- Do you speak French or Italian? - English at home.
在学校说法文 我上音乐学校（法语）
Francais a L 'ecole. The Music Conservatory in Vevey.
但现在爷爷给我请家教了
But Grandfather's having me tutored now.
他坚持让我念大学
He insists I go to college.
哦 只要能上大学 我甚至愿意去干谋杀
Oh, I'd commit murder to go to college.
事实上 我是要去欧洲
Actually, I'm going to Europe.
这个嘛 至少我希望我能去
Well, at least I hope I am.
我马屈姑婆说她总有一天会去...她得带我去
My Great-Aunt March says she'll go one of these days... and she has to take me with her
因为我可以做她的同伴 我得念好几个小时的书给她听
because I work as her companion. I have to read to her for hours and hours.
不过我会给所有的角色配音！
But I do all the voices!
我相信你会的
I'll bet you do.
如果我不是立志要成为一个作家...
If I weren't going to be a writer...
我就会去纽约外加从事舞台工作了
I'd go to New York and pursue the stage.
你惊着了吗？
Are you shocked?
很惊讶
Very.
对...对不起
I...I'm sorry.
对不起 不过梅格在家总要让我扮演男士的角色
I'm sorry. Meg always makes me take the gentleman's part at home.
只可惜你不了解女士的角色
It's a shame you don't know the lady's part.
你为啥要看我裙子的背面？
Why are you looking at the back of my dress?
它并不太难看！实话实说
It isn't so bad! Honestly.
你答应不看的
You promised you wouldn't look.
哦 乔 我扭伤了我的脚踝
Oh, Jo, I've sprained my ankle.
穿这样的鞋 是我的话就不会奇怪了！痛吗？
I shouldn't wonder in those shoes! Does it hurt?
哦 不 不 不 我很好 谢谢
Oh. Oh, no, no. I'm quite well, thank you.
哈 这是我们的邻居 罗利 那个俘虏
（乔在引用狄更斯小说中的角色）
Well, this is our neighbor, Laurie, the captive.
喔 可怜的梅格 我去跟嘉丁纳太太说
Oh, poor Meg. I'll go tell Mrs. Gardiner.
噢 别 乔 她会以为我喝了潘趣酒
（潘趣酒，一种源于印度的果汁鸡尾酒）
Oh, no, Jo. She'll think I've been sampling the punch.
这会把这么完美的派对给破坏的
A perfectly good party ruined.
我有马车 让我送你回家
I have my carriage. Let me take you home.
-哦 真好！ -不 谢谢
- Oh, yes! - Oh, no, thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
靠着我
Lean on me.
谢谢你 罗伦斯先生 你真是太好了
Thank you, Mr. Laurence. That's very kind of you.
不客气
Not at all.
-晚安 罗利 -晚安 马屈小姐
- Good-bye, Laurie. - Good night, Miss. March.
你这鞋哪儿来的？
Wherever did you get this shoe?
你们坐了他的马车？哦 你俩真是幸运
Did you ride in his carriage? Oh, you two have all the luck.
喔 乔 他很浪漫吗？
Oh, Jo, is he very romantic?
一点也不！
Not in the slightest!
我们很感谢他
We're very much obliged to him,
但他是个糟糕的男孩子
but he's a dreadful boy.
他做的很好 用雪敷在你的脚踝上
He did a good deed putting snow on this ankle.
他把雪敷在你脚踝上？
He put snow on your ankle?
睡觉去 艾米小姐
To bed, Miss Amy.
他亲手弄的？
With his own hands?
噢 别那么神魂颠倒的
Oh, stop being so swoony.
我可不希望我的女儿们对男孩子们做傻事 睡觉去
I won't have my girls being silly about boys. To bed,
乔 带她去
Jo, dear.
还痛吗？
Does this hurt?
所有好事都让梅格遇上了
Everything lovely happens to Meg.
哦 的确如此！
Oh, yes indeed!
你不可以像学校的笨女孩那样...对罗利感情用事
You mustn't be soppy about Laurie anymore than you should be soppy... about those silly girls at school.
我希望我们能和他成为好朋友
I hope we shall be good friends with him.
和一个男孩做朋友？
With a boy?
他不是男孩！他是罗利！
He isn't a boy! He's Laurie!
快点！
Faster!
您的小姐们异常活跃 马屈太太 如果我可以这么说的话
Your young ladies are unusually active, Mrs. March, if I may say so.
你的确可以这么说 布鲁克先生
You may indeed, Mr. Brooke.
在我看来 年轻的女孩和男孩没有什么不同…他们需要努力运动
It is my opinion that young girls are no different than boys...in their need for exertion.
女性身体虚弱和易晕厥...
Feminine weakness and fainting spells are the direct result...
是我们限制年轻女孩子在家里穿着束腹 并且弯腰做针线活的直接结果
of our confining young girls to the house... bent over their needlework in restrictive corsets.
妈咪！
Marmee!
你的年轻学生是个运动员
Your young student is an athlete.
他 谢谢夸奖 是个好运动员
He is, thank you, a good one.
但是个不守规矩的学生
But he makes an unruly scholar.
我很遗憾他的祖父经常不在家
I regret that his grandfather is away much.
希望你的女儿们…能给他更温和的影响
One hopes that your girls...will be a gentling influence.
是呀 布鲁克先生
Indeed, Mr. Brooke.
妈咪 你非得跟所有人说束腹的事吗？
Marmee, must you speak to everyone about corsets?
哦 梅格 我有提吗？
Oh, Meg. Do I?
我靠 这些该死的裙子
Blast these wretched skirts!
别说我靠和该死
Don't say blast and wretch.
艾米 别那么傻
Amy, don't be such a ninny-pinny.
我希望我是贝丝 那样就能待在家里做些高兴事
I wish I was Beth so I could stay home and do pleasant things.
噢 如果你把洗衣服和做家事称作高兴事就行！
Oh, if you call doing laundry and housework pleasant!
我靠！
Blast!
艾米 快呀 我工作要迟到了
Amy, hurry. I'll be late for work.
金太太来了 我又迟到了
There's Mrs. King. I'm tardy again.
可爱的孩子
Lovely children.
噢 梅格 我必须去上学吗?我很“吴用”
Oh, Meg, must I go to school? I'm so "degradatated."
我简直无地自容 我还欠至少一打的莱姆果
（莱姆果，一种类似酸橙的水果，学生常用作货币）
I can hardly hold my head up. I owe at least a dozen limes.
-莱姆果？ -现在莱姆果很流行吗？
- Limes? - Are limes the fashion now?
当然 现在就莱姆果好用
Of course they are. It's nothing but limes now.
大家把莱姆果藏在桌子里 用它交换珠子和其他东西 然后课间所有女孩都拿它们互相款待
Everyone keeps them in their desks and trades them for beads and things. And all the girls treat each other in recess.
如果你不带莱姆果到学校 你就完了 你还不如死掉算了
If you don't bring limes to school, you're nothing. You might as well be dead.
我曾有很多莱姆果 而我现在一个也付不起了
I've had ever so many limes, and I can't pay anyone back.
难怪你在学校什么都学不到！
No wonder you don't learn anything at that school!
我知道没有一点小奢侈品的感受
I know how it feels to do without any little luxuries.
但我们并不是一贫如洗 至少目前还不是
But we are not destitute, not yet.
这有两毛五 妈咪这个月给了我零用钱
Here's a quarter. Marmee gave me the rag money this month.
去吧！
Go on!
“第二 灵魂的不朽被认为是由于它的非物质性...
"Secondly, the immortality of the soul is asserted to be in consequence of its immateriality...
就像在所有的宗教案例中一样...
as in all leipothymic cases...
与不朽...
consistent with the idea of immortality...
和非道德，以及肉体的观念相一致...”
and immorality, and physicality..."
而我想你终于睡着了
And I think you finally dozed off.
乔瑟芬 你有封信！
Josephine, there's a draft!
是爸爸的消息吗？
Is it Father?
老师打了我
Teacher struck me.
他把莱姆果丢到雪地里
He put the limes out into the snow.
玫·切斯特说我的莱姆果烂透了 一定曾捐给希望之家
May Chester said my limes must have been donated to Hope House.
然后我说她休想从我这儿再拿到一个莱姆果
Then I said that she wouldn't get a single lime from me.
然后她告诉老师戴维斯先生 莱姆果藏在我桌子里 然后他就打了我
And then she told Mr. Davis they were hidden in my desk...and then he struck me.
我们应该过去用他的棍子把他的肥油打出来!
We oughta go over there and beat the tar out of him with his own stick!
乔 我们不接受暴力
Jo, we must not embrace violence.
我会写封信给他
I'll write this man a letter.
-写信？ -那会让他明白他错了
- A letter? - That'll show him.
你没告诉我莱姆果是被学校禁止带的 那可是整整一个月的零用钱啊?
You failed to mention to me they were forbidden. A whole month's rag money?
艾米 我不该拿钱给你的
Amy, I shouldn't have given it to you.
对不起！
I'm sorry!
那些可爱的莱姆果呀 我完全“荒凉”了
（年幼的艾米不会用词）
All those lovely limes. I'm perfectly "desolated."
你失去莱姆果算不了什么
I'm not sorry you lost them.
这时候它是一个无关紧要的事
It's a frivolous concern in times like these.
你更想重塑你亲爱的小鼻子…而不是塑造你的性格
You are more intent upon reshaping your dear little nose...than in fashioning your character.
那是所可怕的学校！难怪你拼字那么糟...你的拉丁语那么荒谬
It's an appalling school. Your spelling's atrocious... your Latin absurd.
戴维斯先生说了 教育女人...和训练母猫一样有用
Mr. Davis said it was as useful to educate a woman... as to educate a female cat.
我要勒死戴维斯先生！
I shall strangle Mr. Davis!
“致戴维斯先生...
" Mr. Davis...
你有什么权利打一个孩子？
what right have you to strike a child?
在上帝的眼中 我们都是孩子 我们都是平等的
In God's eyes we are all children and we are all equals.
如果你殴打和羞辱一个孩子
If you hit and humiliate a child,
那么她唯一学到的教训是...就是打骂和羞辱"
the only lesson she will learn...is to hit and humiliate."
艾米 你觉得你能约束自己...像贝丝那样在家里学习吗?
Amy, do you think you can discipline yourself... to learn at home as Beth has done?
“我要我女儿艾米从你学校退学”
"I withdraw my daughter Amy from your school."
这坏蛋活该!
It serves the scoundrel right!
乔现在会监督你的教育工作
Jo will now supervise your education.
乔 告诉我接下来的故事发生了什么...
Jo, tell me what happens next...
在公爵抛弃家产 拯救礼拉夫人之后
after the Duke turns his back on his family fortune and saves Lady Zara.
不知道 全是谋杀和打斗
Don't know. It's all murder and gore.
-那少女身陷危难 -我喜欢你的少女身陷危难
-The damsel's in distress. -Oh, I love your damsels in distress.
哦 贝丝 说真的
Oh, Beth, truly,
我不知道我能否像妈咪那么善良
I don't know if I could ever be good like Marmee.
我宁愿使用暴力
I rather crave violence.
要是我能像爸爸一样...
If only I could be like Father...
去打仗 站起来反抗不公正的世界
and go to war and stand up to the lions of injustice.
妈咪也是如此 只是用她自己的方式而已
And so Marmee does in her own way.
是的
Yes.
但我想做点不同的事情！
But I want to do something different!
我还不知道是什么 不过我正在找
I don't know what it is yet, but I'm on the watch for it.
你会找到的 乔
You will find it, Jo.
哈啰！乔！过来这里
Hello! Jo! Come over here.
还有你 梅格
You too, Meg.
这附近沉闷得像坟墓一样
It's dull as tombs around here.
罗伦斯先生 一个人不能像对牛那样对女士们大喊大叫
Mr. Laurence, one doesn't shout at ladies as if they were cattle.
我道歉
My apologies.
好啦
All right.
那些女孩子整天在那儿做什么？
What do those girls do over there all day?
女性生活的秘密...
Over the mysteries of female life...
就像被面纱蒙上的脸 最好别去打扰
there is drawn a veil, best left undisturbed.
哦 亲爱的伯爵夫人 请为我祈祷...
Oh, dear Countess, pray for me...
因为我和我的亲哥哥罗吉戈犯下原罪 品尝了禁果
for I have sinned against meself and me brother Rodrigo.
你应该说重读“犯下原罪” 这样才能表示你真的犯了原罪
You've got to say sinned as if you've really sinned!
犯下原罪！
Sinned!
罗吉戈！
Rodrigo!
你是来找兰克斯郡公爵的
You arrive seeking the Duke of Lankershire.
喂 谁在那儿？
Hark ye. Who goes there?
哦 我忘敲铜钹了
Oh, I forgot the cymbals.
怎么...
Why it’s...
那是罗吉戈！
it's Rodrigo!
罗吉戈？
Rodrigo?
我要扮裴莉特夫人
I want to be Lady Violet.
我“倦厌”演那个男孩了
（艾米再次用错单词）
I'm "exhaustified" of being the boy.
戏剧就是人生 艾米！
The play is the thing, Amy!
你扮裴莉特夫人还太小
You're too little to be Lady Violet.
那 你来演我的蒙太内斯库伯爵夫人吧
Here, be the Countess de Montanescu.
你的角色一句台词都没有
You don't have any lines.
那谁来扮我们的罗吉戈哥哥？
Besides who would be our Rodrigo?
各位先生...
Gentlemen...
我提议允许一位新会员 加入我们的戏剧社
I propose the admission of a new member to our theatrical society.
西奥多·罗伦斯 我们投票表决
Theodore Laurence. We'll put it to a vote.
不 他会嘲讽我们的表演 以后还会取笑我们
Nay. He'll laugh at our acting and poke fun at us later.
他会认为这只是个游戏
He'll think it's only a game.
不 他不会的 作为一个绅士 我保证
No, he won't. Upon my word as a gentleman.
乔 只有女士在场的时候 我们才可以无拘无束一点
Jo, when it's only ladies, we don't guard our conduct in the same way.
我们才可以袒露我们的灵魂 说出最可怕的秘密
We bear our souls and tell the most appalling secrets.
不然他会发现我们举止不当的
He would find us improper.
泰迪不会做这种事的
Teddy would do nothing of the sort.
噢 拜托？我们试试他 好吗？
Oh, please? Let's try him. Shall we?
-叛徒！ -各位艺术家
-Traitor! -Fellow artists,
请允许我介绍一下...作为一个演员 一个音乐家
may I present myself...as an actor, a musician,
也是这个俱乐部忠诚而谦逊的仆人
and a loyal and very humble servant of the club.
我们自有论断
We'll be the judge of that.
为表达我的感谢之情
In token of my gratitude,
及促进两国沟通...
and as a means of promoting... communication between adjoining nations...
由于现在禁止窗口喊叫
shouting from windows being forbidden,
所以我将提供...
I shall provide...
一个挂在树篱上的邮筒...
a post office in our hedge...
以此来进一步鼓励
to further encourage
袒露我们的灵魂...
the baring of our souls...
说出我们最可怕的秘密的行为
and the telling of our most appalling secrets.
我谨承诺...
I do pledge...
永远不会泄露我在这里得到的秘密
never to reveal what I receive in confidence here.
既然这样...
Well then...
请就位吧 罗吉戈
do take your place, Rodrigo.
罗吉戈...爵士
Sir...Rodrigo.
于是罗利被我们的戏剧社所接纳...
And so Laurie was admitted as an equal into our society...
而我们马屈家的女孩可以享受拥有一个真正兄弟般的新奇生活了…
and we March girls could enjoy the daily novelty...of having a real brother of our very own.
我要去戏院 我哪儿也没去过
I want to go to the theater. I never get to go anywhere.
你太小了 贝丝 妈咪看戏的眼镜呢？
You're too little. Beth, where in tarnation are Marmee's opera glasses?
我不小了 你们只是想霸占罗利
I'm not too little. You're just hogging Laurie.
拜托 我不能去吗？
Please, can't I go?
喔 艾米 我怕罗利只预定了四个座位 我看起来是不是太寒酸了？
Oh, Amy, I'm afraid Laurie only reserved four seats. Do I look too shabby?
哦 天哪 梅格 这又不是加冕典礼
Oh, Jehoshaphat, Meg, this isn't a coronation.
只是罗利和那个可怕的布鲁克先生而已
It's just Laurie and that awful Mr. Brooke.
乔 你不能向泰迪再要张票吗？
Jo, can't you ask Teddy to get another ticket?
不!
No!
你感冒了 亲爱的
You have a cold, dear.
-闭上眼睛 -依芙琪琳和我去沏茶
-Rest your eyes. -Evangeline and I will make you some ginger tea.
你的代数学落了好几个礼拜
You're weeks behind in algebra.
划记号那几页都要写 我可不想有个懒惰无知的妹妹
Do all the pages that I've marked. I won't have a sister who's a lazy ignoramus.
别生闷气 你看起来像只鸽子
Don't sulk. You look like a pigeon.
晚安
Good night.
你会后悔的 乔·马屈！
You'll be sorry for this, Jo March!
谢谢
Thank you.
哦 内尔·沃森太太 她还真是个完美的花痴啊？
（沃森太太，片中戏院的剧中人物）
Oh, Mrs. Nell Watson. Wasn't she a wonderful swooner?
-如果我是那种让犯花痴的人就好了! -如果我是那种让犯花痴的人就好了
-If only I were the swooning type! -If only I were the catching type.
小罗伦斯告诉我...你是一个戏剧迷 马屈小姐
Young Laurence informs me...you are an aficionado of the theater, Miss March.
这个 我...我喜欢读剧本
Well, I...I enjoy reading plays.
是呀 我 我觉得这是最令人愉快的经历
Yes. I, I find it most pleasurable myself.
虽然我得承认 我在剧院的时候...
Though I confess I'm distracted at the theater...
一想到演员们的特殊生活我就分心了
thinking of the peculiar lives of the actors themselves.
每当我想到沃森太太所遭受的粗暴对待时...
When one considers the immodesties Mrs. Nell Watson suffers...
总怀疑什么样的女人会愿意过这种生活
one wonders what sort of lady would seek such a life.
梅格可是个出色的女演员！
Meg is a sensational actress!
我们总是演疯狂的戏剧
We're always putting on wild theatricals.
这只是我们玩的游戏
It's just something that we play at.
嗯 事实上...在学校里 我参加过辩论
Well, as, as a matter of fact...at school I engaged in debating.
你觉得怎么样？
What do you think of that?
让我们去看他们做什么
Let's see what they do.
-我玩得很愉快 布鲁克先生 -我也是
- I had a wonderful time, Mr. Brooke. - As did I.
这是最快乐的一晚 我很想...
It was a most delightful evening. And I'd very much like...
非常感谢你 晚安
Thank you very much. Good night.
哦 晚安
Oh, good night.
这是不礼貌的
That was rude.
你醉倒在他怀里了
You plastered yourself on him.
-当男士举起手臂时 牵手是一种礼貌 -戏怎么样？
-It's proper to take a gentleman's arm if it's offered. -How was the theater?
有趣吗？
Amusing?
简直棒极了！我完全被那个爱情场景给震撼了
It was wonderful! I was absolutely inspired by the love scene.
你脸红了 亲爱的梅格 戏院很挤吗？
You look flushed, Meg dear. Was the theater overcrowded?
还生闷气呢？
Still sulking?
贝丝 我把手稿放哪儿去了
Beth, where did I put my manuscript?
不！
No!
不是我做的！
I didn't do it!
我要杀了你！
I'm gonna kill you!
我要杀了你！我要杀了你！
I'm gonna kill you! I'm gonna kill you!
我要杀了你！你听见没有？
I'm gonna kill you! Do you hear me?
你怎么可以这么对我？
How can you do this to me?
乔 住手 你伤着她了
Jo, stop. You're hurting her.
乔！乔！放开她！怎么回事？
Jo! Jo! Let go of her! What's happened?
我恨你！我恨你！
I hate you! I hate you!
别碰它 让它烧了算了
Don't touch it. Just let it go.
来吧 就让它烧了吧
Come. Just let it go.
你死定了！你什么都不是！
You're dead! You're nothing!
我永远都不要再见到你！
I never want to see you again!
这是很大的损失 而你绝对有权利生气
It is a very great loss, and you have every right to be put out.
但别带着怒气入睡
But don't let the sun go down upon your anger.
原谅彼此
Forgive each other.
明天重新开始 好吗？
Begin again tomorrow, huh?
我永远都不会原谅她
I will never forgive her.
对不起 乔
I'm sorry, Jo.
看来这是我们今年最后一次玩雪了
（乔和罗利前往城郊的瓦尔登湖滑雪）
Looks like the last ice we'll have this year.
喊“出发”
Say "go."
罗利 乔 等我一下！
Laurie, Jo, wait for me!
别理她
Ignore her.
准备...我靠！
Ready... Blast!
乔 拜托！
Jo, please!
艾米！
Amy!
撑住！
Hold on.
我来了！我来了！
I'm coming! I'm coming!
撑住 艾米
Hold on, Amy.
找根横木！
Get a rail!
抓住木棍 艾米
Grab the stick, Amy.
快！
Come on!
撑住！
Hold on!
很好 对了 就这样 很好
There we go. That's it, that's it.
乔瑟芬·马屈 你大老远从瓦尔登湖过来...就只穿这件灯笼裤？
Josephine March, you walked all the way from Walden Pond...in only these bloomers?
说的好像她拿这当回事似的 亲爱的艾米
As if she even noticed. Dear Amy.
我怎么可能这么糟糕？
How could I have been so horrible?
感谢上帝罗利在场
Thank God for Laurie.
乔 你爱罗利胜过爱我吗？
Jo, do you love Laurie more than you love me?
哦 别像只可笑的甲虫似的！
Oh, don't be such a beetle!
我不可能像爱我姐妹一样去爱别人
I could never love anyone as I love my sisters.
我不是甲虫
I'm not a beetle.
哦 看来 你漏掉了最精彩的部分
Oh, look out. You're leaving out the best part.
当礼拉夫人屈从公爵的死敌时
When Lady Zara succumbs to the Duke's rival.
哦 是的 对了！是休果公爵
Oh, right, yes! Sir Hugo.
我个人相当的喜欢他！
I quite prefer him myself.
春天的时候 我们把果园屋弄得乱七八糟
In the spring, we turned Orchard House upside down...
为梅格参加莎莉·莫法特的社交宴会做准备
with preparations for Meg to attend Sally Moffat's coming out.
至于我自己 则宁可被吊死 也不参加化妆舞会
Myself, I'd sooner have been hung by the neck than attend a fancy ball.
等全波士顿人见你这身打扮 梅格
Wait 'til all of Boston sees you in this dress, Meg.
我告诉罗利得好好的炫耀一下你 不要让你像朵要死的靠墙花似的
I told Laurie he has to show you off and keep you from being a wallflower...upon penalty of death.
哦 那悲惨的手套在那儿？
Oh, where is that miserable glove?
阿比盖尔 我对你安排梅格的方式很是摇头
Abigail, I shake my head at the way you're managing Margaret.
她怎么能不露个面就结婚呢?
How is she to be married without a proper debut?
现在 姨妈 以我们的状况...
Now, Auntie, in our present circumstances...
你们的状况 就算你丈夫回来也不会变
Your circumstances will not change with your husband's return.
我外甥对钱的愚蠢程度就和他埋首研究的新哲学一样
My nephew is as foolish with money as he is in his new philosophies.
你家唯一的希望是让梅格嫁个好人家...
The one hope for your family is for Margaret to marry well...
虽然我不知道谁会去娶家庭女教师
though I don't know who marries governesses.
妈咪！
Marmee!
而这一位会彻底毁了她爱看书的性格
And this one has entirely ruined her disposition with books.
哦 是给我的吗 乔瑟芬？
Oh, are those for me, Josephine?
不 梅格要带去莫法特家
No. Meg's taking them to the Moffat's.
妈咪 梅格快疯了 她手套丢了 而她只有一付
Marmee, Meg's frantic. She lost her glove, and she only has one pair.
她不能不戴手套去 莫法特是此地的望族
She cannot go without gloves. The Moffats are society.
你说的完全正确
You're absolutely correct.
告诉梅格她可以借我的用
Tell Meg she may borrow mine.
梅格 你可以拿妈咪的！
Meg, you can take Marmee's!
哦 亲爱的！
Oh, dear!
-再加点茶？ -不，谢谢
- More tea? - No, thank you.
莎莉·莫法特
Sally Moffat,
你撑得都快拉不紧束腹带了
you won't be able to draw your laces.
在我的初次社交派对之前 我几星期都没吃饭
At my coming out party, I didn't eat for weeks beforehand.
哦 梅格 我喜欢你身上的这颜色
Oh, Meg, I do like that color on you.
它就像勿忘我花一样
It's just like forget-me-nots.
这是内战爆发以来我见过的最好的布料
The nicest I've seen that kind of fabric since the war broke out.
但是你把它编得如此平凡
But you had it made up so plain.
这个...我...我自己做的缝纫 而且...
Well, I...I do my own sewing, and...
查尔斯街的芬斯特夫人店有现成的丝绸
Mrs. Finster's on Charles Street carries silk pieces ready-made.
明天我带你过去
Tomorrow I'll take you there.
马屈家几年都没买丝绸了
Marches haven't bought silk in years.
他们对奴隶制度有意见
They have views on slavery.
梅格 你父亲的学校不得不关闭 不是吗...当他让一个黑人小女孩进来上学的时候?
Meg, isn't it true your father's school had to close...when he admitted a little dark girl?
芬斯特太太家的丝绸不是在南方加工的 就在这里 在林菲尔德
The silk of Mrs. Finster's isn't milled in the South. It's made right here, over in Linfield.
这不会是中国丝吧？
This isn't China silk?
他们用小孩当劳工
They use little children for labor.
所有纺纱厂都这样
All the silk mills do.
穷人总是跟我们在一起
The poor are always with us.
你真好 提醒了我们
You are so good to remind us.
我能告诉你件事吗？
May I tell you something?
这是下午穿的衣服
This is an afternoon dress.
我要你做我腻友
I'm going to make you my pet.
今晚马奇小姐想要多少战利品就有多少战利品
Tonight Miss March shall have as many conquests as she likes.
你没穿束腹
You have no corset.
不 我想下一支是波尔卡舞...能和我一起吗？
No, I believe the next dance is the polka...with me.
我也想你一起 派克先生...
I would dance with you, Mr. Parker...
但我担心我的新鞋
but I fear for my new slippers.
我的信条是 “别踩我”
My credo is, " Don't tread on me."
马屈小姐
Miss March.
我还以为你们家都是戒酒的
I thought your family were temperance people.
罗利
Laurie.
哦 别遮 这里只剩一两位男士...还没见识过你的魅力
Oh, don't cover up. There may be one or two gentlemen here...who haven't seen all of your charms.
我答应过乔要炫耀你的
I did promise Jo I would show you off.
这是那些女孩子替我打扮的 我喜欢
The girls dressed me up, and I rather like it.
是呀 它展露了一个全新的梅格
Yes, it reveals a whole new Meg.
这你怎么说？
What do you call this?
梅格！
Meg!
对不起
I'm sorry.
请别告诉乔我的行为
Please don't tell Jo how I've behaved.
当然不会
Of course not.
只要你不告诉乔我的行为就好
If you won't tell anyone how I've behaved.
我只是在试着扮演一个角色...
I was only playing a part...
想知道作为贝尔·嘉丁纳的感觉...
to see how it felt to be Belle Gardiner...
被求了四次婚 戴过二十付手套
with four proposals and 20 pairs of gloves.
你比他们强十倍
You're worth ten of those other girls.
你们看见那个马屈家的女孩如何追求罗家的嗣子了吗？
Did you see the way this March girl has gone after the Laurence heir?
这可能是马屈家最幸运的事了
Best thing that could happen to the Marches.
哦！这可笑的衣服！我整晚老被它绊倒
Oh! This ridiculous dress! I've been tripping over it all night.
缠一些在你脖子上 它可以让你好受些
Tie something around your neck where it can do you some good.
我讨厌人们说罗利和梅格的闲话...
I don't like people speculating about Laurie and our Meg...
就好像他们是戏剧里的角色一样
as if they were characters in some play.
没什么比看到一个女人自得其乐更能引起人们的闲话了
Nothing provokes speculation more than the sight of a woman enjoying herself.
-为什么罗利可以爱怎么做就怎么做 调情 喝香槟... -而不会有人看不起他是吧?
- Why is it Laurie may do as he likes, flirt and tipple champagne... - And no one thinks the less of him?
这个嘛 我想有个实际的理由
Well, I suppose for one practical reason:
因为罗利是男人 正因如此...
Laurie is a man, and as such...
他可以投票 拥有财产和追求他所爱的职业
he may vote, hold property and pursue any profession he pleases.
所以他不容易被别人看不起
And so he is not so easily demeaned.
为什么会有人在乎别人怎么想？
Why should anyone care what they think?
我就在乎
I do.
能受到表扬和赞美是件好事 我忍不住喜欢它
It's nice to be praised and admired. I couldn't help but like it.
不是这么回事！
Of course not!
我只在乎你自己的想法
I only care what you think of yourself.
如果你觉得你的价值只在于做一个装饰品...
If you feel your value lies in being merely decorative...
恐怕有一天你会发现你自己... 真的相信你只是这样
I fear that someday you might find yourself...believing that's all that you really are.
时间会腐蚀所有外表的美
Time erodes all such beauty,
但时间无法消灭...
but what it cannot diminish...
你心灵的美好
is the wonderful workings of your mind.
你的幽默 你的友爱...以及你在道德上的勇气
Your humor, your kindness...and your moral courage.
这些是我所珍爱的你心中的东西
These are the things I cherish so in you.
我真希望能给我女孩子们一个更公平的世界
I so wish I could give my girls a more just world.
我知道你们会使它更美好
I know you'll make it a better place.
不 我不现在不需要这些书
No, I don't want them now.
留着曲谱吧 我好久都不会再碰钢琴了
And keep the music. I won't be going near a piano for ages.
你去念大学会需要书的 这是你的《董贝父子》
（《董贝父子》，狄更斯小说）
You need your books in college. Here's your Dombey and Sons.
我可以发誓还有另一卷的
I could've sworn there was another volume.
老实说 乔...我不会把狄更斯的书都带到哈佛去
Honestly, Jo...I won't be taking all of Dickens to Harvard with me.
哦 你确实不会 你有更重要的东西要学习
Oh, no. You'll have much more important things to read.
什么都不会改变的 乔
Nothing's going to change, Jo.
我希望我能去大学
I wish I could go.
我也希望你能去
I wish you could too.
你会学到各种我不会的东西 然后我会讨厌你
You'll come back knowing all sorts of things I don't know...and then I'll hate you.
这个嘛 这已经发生了...
Well, as it happens...
我就知道一些你不知道的事
I already know something you don't know.
是关于梅格...
About Meg...
和我的某位前任家教的...
and a certain former tutor of mine...
此人很快将受聘于罗伦斯父子公司
soon to be employed at the firm of Laurence and Laurence.
撒谎
Liar.
梅格是否曾错放过某件私人物品 像是...
Has Meg mislaid a certain personal article such as...
一只手套？
a glove?
梅格 约翰·布鲁克偷了你的手套！
Meg, John Brooke stole your glove!
什么手套？不...不会是白色的那只吧？
What glove? N-Not my white one?
布鲁克偷走很久了 罗利说他把它放在自己的口袋里
Brooke's had it forever. Laurie says he keeps it in his pocket.
你得要他交回手套 汉娜 你也认为他该还回来不是吗？
You must tell him to return it. Hannah, don't you think he oughta give it back?
我怎么想并不重要
'Tisn't what I think that matters.
乔？梅格？
Jo? Meg?
这是...华盛顿医院来的电报
It's, uh, a telegram ...from Washington Hospital.
你们爸爸受伤了
Your father's been wounded.
快呀 艾米 就这样了
Come on, Amy. That's it.
家庭账本在这里 这该够你们用到月底
The household account is in this ledger. It should see you through the month.
当然 别担心我们
Of course. Don't worry about us.
哦 贝丝 亲爱的 帮我照顾汉默家 好吗？
Oh, Beth, dear. Look in on the Hummels for me, will you?
我会的 妈咪
I will, Marmee.
乔在哪呢？都快6点了
Where's Jo? It's almost 6:00.
她正为了车票和马屈姑婆干仗呢
Doing battle with Aunt March for Marmee's railway ticket.
你能带信到希望之家给尤巴太太吗？
Would you carry a letter to Mrs. Juba at the Hope House.
约翰！
John!
布鲁克先生
Mr. Brooke.
我是自荐来护送你妈妈的
I've come to offer myself as an escort to your mother.
厨师把这个打包了...爷爷给马奇先生送了一瓶烈酒
Cook packed this up...and Grandfather sends a bottle of spirits for Mr. March.
太好了 谢谢 罗利
That's lovely. Thank you, Laurie.
布鲁克先生来了
Mr. Brooke is here.
-马屈太太 -布鲁克先生
-Mrs. March. -Mr. Brooke.
小罗伦斯不再需要家庭教师了...罗伦斯先生在华盛顿为我安排了工作
As young Laurence no longer requires a tutor...Mr. Laurence has commissions for me in Washington.
我希望能为你服务 我们不能让你单独旅行
I should like to be of service to you there. We couldn't let you travel alone.
布鲁克先生 你真体贴
Mr. Brooke, how kind of you.
-让我来？ -谢谢
- May I? - Thank you.
我们要乘6点的火车去吗?
Are we to go on the 6:00 train?
是的 我让乔去买的车票 但她还没...
Yes, I sent Jo off, but she hasn't...
我来了!
I'm here!
乔 总算到了
Jo. Finally.
25美元？姑婆舍得给这么多？
Twenty-five. Can Aunt March spare this?
我不能忍受向她要钱
I couldn't bear to ask her.
我卖了我的头发
I sold my hair.
乔 你怎么可以？
Jo, how could you?
你可是个美人啊
You're one beauty.
这不会影响联军战况的 它能再长回来
It isn't going to affect the state of the Union. It'll grow back.
短发很适合你
It suits you.
告诉爸爸我们爱他
Tell Father that we love him.
-告诉他 我们为他祈祷 -带他回家
- Tell him we pray for him. - Bring him home.
-我不会忘记他的好 -汉娜，谢谢
- I'll never forget his kindness. - Hannah, thank you.
啊 我会想念我的小妇人们
Oh, I shall miss my little women.
你是在想念父亲吗？
Are you thinking about Father?
不 想念我的头发
No. My hair.
-再用力点 -是啊 我打中他的头了
- A little harder. - Yeah, I hit him on the noggin.
等等我！
Wait for me!
我靠！
Blast!
-哦 亲爱的 这炉子 -我们还是会吃的
- Oh, dear. This stove! - We'll eat them anyway.
没有玉米粉和咖啡了 杂货店不让我们挂帐了
There's no more cornmeal nor coffee. The grocer won't let us have more on account.
我能带什么给汉默家？
What can I bring the Hummels?
哦 别管汉默家了！上周你在那儿待了几个小时
Oh, fry the Hummels! You spent hours there last week.
-他家的男孩子们病了 –我不能写信告诉妈咪这事
- The boys are sick. - I mustn't write of this to Marmee.
她的负担够重了
She has enough burdens now.
我痛恨金钱！
I hate money!
你们的马铃薯！
Your potatoes!
快呀！这里！
Come on! Here!
晾干床垫 小心清洗
Air the beds. And be careful cleaning.
-别忘了你的学习 艾米 –我不会忘
- And don't forget your studies, Amy. - I won't.
我会的 走吧！
I will. Go!
哦 贝丝！
Oh, Beth!
我不懂你在说啥 我给你们带了一个土豆来
I don't understand. I brought you a potato.
-罗利回家度周末了！ -毫无疑问 他们也缺钱了
- Laurie's home for the weekend! - In need of funds, no doubt.
不过他玩台球的钱都够我们买一周的杂货了
We'd have a week's groceries with what he spends on billiards.
哦 天啊！
Oh, Jehoshaphat!
梅格！
Meg!
梅格 你不会相信的！我卖掉了《葛萝塞斯特公爵》这本书！
Meg, you won't believe it! I've sold the Lost Duke of Gloucester!
整整五美元！我是作家了
Five whole dollars! I'm an author!
贝丝
Beth.
汉默家的婴儿病了
The Hummel baby is sick.
我觉得好奇怪
I feel so strange.
她在发高烧 但她说就像受冻一样
She's burning up, but she says that she's freezing.
她渴得很厉害 但她不肯喝水
She has a terrible thirst, but she won't drink.
听来像砒霜中毒 但她看起来更像蕃茄中毒
Sounds like arsenicum, but she looks more like belladonna.
我看见汉默家的人
I saw the Hummels.
两个孩子被带到耶稣那去了 猩红热
Two children taken up to Jesus. Scarlet fever.
你和乔小姐不会受到危害的 你们还是婴儿的时候就得过了
You and Miss Jo won't be harmed. You had it when you were babies.
但 艾米小姐
But, Miss Amy,
我们必须把你送走
we have to send you away.
她不会死的
She won't die.
她会死吗 罗利？
Will she, Laurie?
上帝不会让她死的
God wouldn't let her die.
我不要离开
I don't wanna go away.
我会每天去看你的
I'll come and see you every day.
我发誓 你不会孤单的
I swear it. You won't be alone.
我怕马屈姑婆
I'm afraid of Aunt March.
如果她对你不好...
If she's unkind to you...
我就来带你走
I'll come and take you away.
我们会去哪儿？
Where will we go?
巴黎？
Paris?
如果我得猩红热死了...
If I get scarlet fever and die...
把我装有绿色鸽子的盒子给梅格
give Meg my box with the green doves on it.
绿松石戒指一定要给乔
And Jo must have my turquoise ring.
我会记住的
I'll see to that.
我不要死
I don't wanna die.
我还没被吻过
I've never even been kissed.
我等被吻等了一辈子
I've waited my whole life to be kissed.
如果我再也没有机会了呢？
And what if I miss it?
我告诉你怎么办
I tell you what.
我保证在你死之前吻你
I promise to kiss you before you die.
我不知道 我觉得妈咪不应该离开父亲
I don't know. I don't think Marmee should leave Father.
贝丝需要妈咪 她依赖她
Beth needs Marmee. She depends on her.
但是如果我们把她叫回来 而父亲的伤情更糟了么？
But what if we send for her and Father gets worse?
看在上帝的份上 我们怎么付的起火车钱?
How in the name of all that's holy would we pay for the train?
“他亵渎的不是我的‘绳所’...”
"That he profane not my 'sancteraries'..."
“圣所”
"Sanctuaries.
“圣所
“因此我 上帝 降圣迹给他们”
For I, the Lord, do sanctify them.
而摩西告诉亚伦和他的儿子们...
And Moses told it unto Aaron and to his sons...
and unto all the children of Israel."
以及所有的以色列子民”
(《圣经》中的摩西传教章节)
继续
Go on.
“上帝对摩西说...”
"And the Lord spake unto Moses saying..."
乔 罗伦斯先生来了
Jo, Mr. Laurence is here.
如果可以的话
If we may,
我想让我的私人医师 班斯大夫...检查一下这个小女孩的病情
I wish my personal physician, Dr. Bangs...to examine the little girl.
无能为力了
There's nothing to be done.
如果给她放血 会致她死的
If I bleed her, it would finish her.
-最好请她母亲回来 -原谅我
- Best to send for the mother. - Forgive me.
我已经这么做了 马屈夫人会坐今晚的火车回来
I've already done so. Mrs. March arrives on the train this night.
万福马利亚 满得恩典 主与你同在
Hail Mary, full of grace, the Lord is with thee.
乔
Joe.
小蟋蟀
Cricket,
妈咪回来了
Marmee's here.
跟冰一样冷 乔
Icy cold. Jo.
乔 取一个装有醋水的盆和一些抹布
Jo, fetch a basin with vinegar water and some rags.
梅格 我的医药箱
Meg, my kit.
得让她的头部退烧
Must draw the fever down from her head.
没事 现在没事了
It's all right. It's all right now.
这才是我所爱的孩子
That's my love.
贝丝！
Beth!
就这样亲爱的贝丝回到了我们的身边...
And so our dear Beth came back to us...
但高烧永远使她心脏衰弱
although the fever had weakened her heart forever.
那时我们并不知道 阴影已经降临
We did not know then that a shadow had fallen.
我们准备着另一个没有爸爸的圣诞节
We prepared for another Christmas without Father.
试着挂在每个角落 谢谢
Try each corner. Thank you.
不 不！一个蝴蝶结就够了！
No, no! One bow is enough!
罗伦斯先生 谢谢你
Mr. Laurence. Thank you.
哦 我很抱歉
Oh. I'm so sorry.
这时常发生的
It happens all the time.
她来了！
Here she comes!
这些蝴蝶结怎么办？
What should I do with these bows?
这个 别把她吓死了 她病了 你知道的
Now, don't scare her to death. She's been sick, you know.
椅子藏起来 把它们藏起来 艾米！
Hide the chairs. Hide them, Amy!
这房子真漂亮
The house is beautiful.
他们是我大学的朋友 弗雷迪·沃恩和埃佛·沃森
They're friends of mine from college. Freddy Vaughan and Averill Watson.
他们不会咬人的
They won't bite.
不 别坐那儿！坐在...
No, don't sit there! Sit...
这儿！
Here.
坐这儿孩子
Sit here child.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
我早该把它送给你
I should have given it to you long ago.
这是我小女儿的...
It belonged to my little girl...
她很小就去世了
who had to leave us when she was very young.
但是现在 它又将弹奏出音乐了
But now, it will make music again.
谢谢你 罗伦斯先生。
Thank you, Mr. Laurence.
圣诞快乐！
Merry Christmas!
弹点什么吧 贝丝
Play something, Beth.
要吗？
Shall I?
用冬青枝妆点厅堂
♪ Deck the halls with boughs of holly  Fa la la la la...La la la la ♪
这是属于欢乐的季节
♪ 'Tis the season to be jolly Fa la la la la...La la la la ♪
让我们穿上华丽衣裳
♪ Don we now our gay apparel Fa la la la la...La la la la ♪
轮唱那古老的圣诞颂歌
♪ Troll the ancient yuletide carol Fa la la la la...La la la la ♪
看闪亮佳节呈现眼前
♪ See the blazing yule before us Fa la la la la...La la la la ♪
弹奏竖琴 加入合唱
♪ Strike the harp and join the chorus Fa la la la la...La la la la ♪
跟随着我的快乐旋律
♪ Follow me in merry measure Fa la la la la...La la la la ♪
当我诉说那圣诞宝藏
♪ While I tell of yuletide treasure Fa la la la la...La la la la ♪
真好
That was good.
我担心你的婚约还要很久
I fear you would have a long engagement.
三四年吧 约翰得在和你结婚前有个房子...
Three or four years. John must secure a house before you can marry...
而且他还得给联邦政府服兵役
and he must do a service to the Union.
约翰？结婚？
John? Marry?
你指那无趣的老布鲁克？
You mean that pokey old Mr. Brooke?
他是怎么和这个家扯上关系的？
How did he weasel his way into this family?
乔
Joe.
约翰很体贴 每天到医院探望父亲
John has been very kind to go visit father in the hospital every day.
他像香粉般无趣 梅格
He's dull as powder. Meg,
你就不能嫁给有趣点的人吗？
can't you at least marry someone amusing?
我中意布鲁克先生
I'm fond of Mr. Brooke.
他是个好人 善良而严肃…
He's a good man. He's kind and serious...
还有 我不怕穷
and I'm not afraid of being poor.
妈咪 你不能让她嫁给他
Marmee, you can't just let her go and marry him.
我不会随便嫁给任何人
I'd hardly just go and marry anyone.
我宁愿梅格为爱结婚 成为穷人的妻子...
I would rather Meg marry for love and be a poor man's wife...
也比为了财富而结婚 失去自尊要好
than marry for riches and lose her self-respect.
所以说你不在意约翰穷？
So you don't mind that John is poor?
不 但我希望他有个房子
No, but I would rather he have a house.
为什么一定得结婚？
Why must we marry at all?
为什么就不能维持现状？
Why can't things just stay as they are?
这只是求婚 不必决定什么
It is only a proposal. Nothing need be decided.
听着 女孩们...别糟蹋这一天
Now, girls...let's not spoil the day.
倾听天使歌颂
♪ Hark the herald angels sing ♪
荣耀归于新生王
♪ Glory to the newborn king ♪
世界和平
♪ Peace on earth ♪
爸爸！爸爸！
Father! Father!
圣诞快乐！各位
Merry Christmas, everyone.
多好的圣诞礼物！
What a wonderful Christmas present!
哦 爸爸 你回家了！
Oh, Father, you're home!
噢 你比以前还英俊了！
Oh, you're more handsome than ever!
贝丝 我的小甜饼 感谢上帝你平安了
Beth, my little cookie. Thank God you're well.
给这人一点空间呼吸吧
Give the man room to breathe.
乔!噢 我的野丫头！
Jo! Oh, my wild girl!
这个 可能会流行哦
Well, this could become the fashion.
-当心别碰他的胳膊 小心 -我不习惯这样
- Watch his arm. Be careful. - I'm not used to this.
别把我这军人宠坏了
Don't coddle this soldier too much.
哦 爸爸！
Oh, Father!
汉娜 上帝祝福你 很高兴见到你
Hannah, God bless you. It's good to see you.
很高兴你回家 马奇先生。
It's good to have you home, Mr. March.
现在 让我瞧瞧我的女儿们
Now, let me look at my girls.
拿走 把它们给...
Take them and give them...
霍乱夺走的人命比叛军多 我所了解是这样 先生
The cholera took more men than the Rebs, as I understand it, sir.
学校不教农艺 但这应该是必修的
Agriculture isn't taught, and it should be required.
也许这些奴隶成为自由人之后应该在西部获得土地。
Perhaps the freedmen should be given land in the West.
你和约翰怎么了？
What happened between you and John?
你别管
Never you mind.
这不是很好吗 乔？
Isn't it wonderful, Jo?
是的 太好了
Yes, it's wonderful.
（四年后）
万物之主我们向您致敬
♪ Lord of all to Thee we raise ♪
这是我们感恩赞美的颂歌
♪ This our hymn of grateful praise ♪
转变肯定会到来
Change will come as surely
犹如四季更迭 而且来得更快
as the seasons and twice as quick.
我们尽力泰然处之...
We make our peace with it as best we can...
就像艾米小时候曾说的
or as Amy once said when she was still a little girl:
“我们总有一天会长大 我们该想清楚自己要什么”
"We'll all grow up someday. We might as well know what we want. "
万物之主我们向您致敬
♪ Lord of all to Thee we raise ♪
这是我们感恩赞美的颂歌
♪ This our hymn of grateful praise ♪
万物之主我们向您致敬
♪ Lord of all to Thee we raise ♪
这是我们感恩赞美的颂歌
♪ This our hymn of grateful praise ♪
所以 你觉得我们的艾米有天份？
So you feel our Amy has talent?
噢 马屈小姐十分擅长绘画...
Oh, Miss March excels at drawing...
但 你知道的 她的风景画缺少情感
but, you know, her landscapes lack emotion.
我确信艾米会从进一步的学习中获益...
I definitely feel Amy would benefit from further study...
但她在这里没法更进一层楼
but she won't get it around here.
你建议去哪里？
Where do you suggest?
科德角有一个很好的艺术家群体...但欧洲才是最好的地方
(科德角，美国地名)
Cape Cod has a fine artist colony...but Europe is the best place.
泰迪 泰迪
Teddy, Teddy.
你的管家说你要等晚上才能回家
Your houseman said you wouldn't be home till night.
我等不了很久
I couldn't wait so long.
为毕业生欢呼吧！
Hail the conquering graduate!
爷爷感到骄傲吗？
Is Grandfather exceedingly proud?
是的 还一心要把我锁在他的办公室里
Yes, and exceedingly bent on locking me up in one of his offices.
为什么艾米可以给瓷器作画...
Why is it Amy may paint china...
而你可以随意写作...而我却必须得果断地把音乐丢在一边？
and you can scribble away...while I must manfully set my music aside?
所以为什么你得这样呢？
Why must you?
如果我不这样...就得违抗爷爷
If I don't...I'd have to defy Grandfather.
对 但不是违抗整个社会
Yes, and not the whole of society.
但我不能反对这老人
I can't go against the old man.
当我想像自己要过哪种生活时...
When I imagine myself in that life...
我只想到一件事...能让我快乐
I can think of only one thing...that would make me happy.
哦 不 泰迪
Oh, no, Teddy.
泰迪 不要
Teddy, don't.
不 等一下 泰迪
No, wait, Teddy.
我们得理智的谈谈
We have to talk about this reasonably.
从我紧紧盯着你的那一刻起...
I have loved you...
我就爱上了你
since the moment I clamped eyes on you.
有什么能比跟你结婚更理智？
Would could be more reasonable than to marry you?
我们会杀了彼此的
We'd kill each other.
胡说
Nonsense.
你我都无法控制我们的坏脾气
Neither of us can keep our temper.
我能控制...
I can...
除非被激怒
unless provoked.
我们都固执得愚蠢 尤其是你
We're both stupidly stubborn, especially you.
-我们会吵架的 -我不会！
- We'd only quarrel. - I wouldn't!
你连求婚都做不到不吵架
You can't even propose without quarreling.
乔...
Jo...
亲爱的乔
Dear Jo,
我发誓我做一个圣人
I swear I'll be a saint.
我会每次争吵都让你赢
I'll let you win every argument.
我会照顾你和你的家人
I'll take care of you and your family.
我会给你所有你被拒绝过的奢侈生活
I'll give you every luxury you've ever been denied.
你无需靠着写作维生 除非你愿意
You won't have to write unless you want to.
爷爷...要我到英国学做生意
Grandfather...wants me to learn the business in England.
你难道不想我们伦敦四处乱逛吗？
Can't you see us bashing around London?
伦敦
London.
哦 泰迪 我还不够时髦去伦敦
Oh, Teddy, I'm not fashionable enough for London.
你需要的是以一个高贵和优雅的人
You need someone who's elegant and refined.
我要你
I want you.
泰迪 请别逼我
Teddy, please don't ask me.
我非常抱歉 我真的很在乎你...
I'm desperately sorry. I do care for you...
在我心里你是我最亲爱的朋友
In my heart you're my dearest friend.
但我就是没法做一个妻子
I just can't go be a wife.
你说不会 但...你会的
You say you won't, but... you will.
我不会 我不会
I won't. I won't.
有一天...
One day...
你会遇上某个男人
you'll meet some man.
一个好男人 而你会非常爱他
A good man. And you will love him tremendously.
你会为他而生 为他而死
And you will live and die for him.
泰迪 拜托
Teddy, please.
乔 你会的
Joe, you will.
我了解你
I know you.
我会去上吊的...若我在一边目睹的话
And I'll be hanged...if I stand by and watch.
乔 你生病了？
Jo, are you ill?
她拒绝了罗利
She has refused Laurie.
这个 我相信她会改变心意的
Well, I'm sure she can take it back.
这只是个误会
It's just a misunderstanding.
不会的
No.
听他说
Listen to him.
我必须离开
I must get away.
当然
Of course.
马屈姑婆要去法国
Aunt March is going to France.
法国！
France!
那是理想!只要能去我什么都能忍受!
That's ideal! I'll put up with anything to go!
马屈姑婆已经要我去了
Aunt March has asked me to go.
去欧洲？我的欧洲？
To Europe? My Europe?
什么时候？
When?
今天才决定的
It was decided just today.
这个 我现在是她的旅伴了
Well, I am her companion now.
她希望我出国学习绘画...
She wishes me to study painting abroad...
并希望我可能找到一个好归宿
in hopes I might make a good match there.
但也许她不会介意你留在她家里...
But perhaps she wouldn't mind if you stayed at Plumfield...
在我们离开之后
while we are gone.
当然 马奇姑婆更喜欢艾米而不是我
Of course Aunt March prefers Amy over me.
为什么不该她去呢？我又难看又古怪 我还经常说错话
Why shouldn't she? I'm ugly and awkward, and I always say the wrong things.
我莫名其妙地抛弃了完美的求婚
I fly around throwing away perfectly good marriage proposals.
我爱我们家 但我的心性如此不定...
I love our home, but I'm just so fitful...
我无法忍受留在这里了!
that I can't stand being here!
抱歉 我很抱歉 妈咪
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Marmee.
我一定是哪里有毛病
There's just something really wrong with me.
我想改变 但我做不到...
I want to change, but I can't...
我知道我哪里也适应不了
and I just know I'll never fit in anywhere.
乔 你有那么多不凡的才能
Jo, you have so many extraordinary gifts.
你怎能期望过平凡的日子？
How can you expect to lead an ordinary life?
你已经准备好要走出去了 好好利用你的才能
You're ready to go out and find a good use for your talent.
虽然我不知道没有我的乔该怎么办
Although I don't know what I shall do without my Jo.
去吧...拥抱你的自由吧...
Go...and embrace your liberty...
看看能成就什么美事
and see what wonderful things come of it.
罗利避往伦敦并四处游历
Laurie sought his refuge in London and abroad.
妈咪帮我在纽约找到住所...
Marmee helped me find a place in the great city of New York...
就此我跨越了童年 抛下了过往的一切
and so I stepped over the divide between childhood and all that lay beyond.
柯克太太？
Mrs. Kirk?
乔瑟芬！
Josephine!
是我 你还好吗？
Yes. How do you do?
吉帝 米妮 这是马屈小姐
Kitty, Minnie. This is Miss March.
她爸爸是马屈上校 他认识你爸爸
Her father was Colonel March. He knew your papa.
小心走 寇先生
Watch your feet, Mr. Costigan.
请进 亲爱的
Do come in, my dear.
亲爱的贝丝 妈咪的朋友 柯克太太
Dear Beth: Marmee's friend, Mrs. Kirk,
让我感觉像在家里一样
has made me feel quite at home.
我的小学生 吉帝和米妮 是可爱的女孩子
My little students, Kitty and Minnie, are dear girls.
在繁忙的寄宿学校成长真奇特...
How curious to grow up in a busy boarding house...
没父亲 母亲是店主
with no father and your own mother the innkeeper.
离开康柯德时我勇气十足...
I felt bold on leaving Concord...
但我承认 我觉得纽约既粗糙又奇怪...我觉得我自己也很奇怪了
but I confess I find New York rough and strange... and myself strange in it
请把这些东西从桌子那边传过去 非常感谢您 教授
Please pass these down the table. Thank you kindly, Professor.
柯克太太相信我来此是为了...
Mrs. Kirk believes that I am here...
在我屈服于婚姻前...体验过度期的美好
for a brief interlude of sensational experience...before succumbing to a matrimonial fate.
虽然我在这样应用尽有的城市...已经不缺乏什么耸人听闻的体验了
And while there is surely no lack of sensational experience...of every kind available in such a city...
虽然我仍未交上好运 但我希望...
I hope, though I've had no luck yet...
我在这里获得的任何体验都能转变为文学作品...
that any experience I gain here will be strictly literary...
这样我就能把所有浪漫 动人的事凝聚于书页中
and that all events of a romantic or sensational nature...will be entirely confined to the page.
小姐 我们的读者对情感故事和神话故事不感兴趣
Our subscribers are not interested in sentiment and fairy stories, miss.
这不是神话故事
They're not fairy stories.
你可以试试投一个女士杂志
Try one of the ladies' magazines.
我真抱歉 我真笨拙
I'm so sorry. I'm so clumsy.
你知道当我第一次见到你的时候 我想的是…
You know that when first I saw you, I thought...
“啊！她是个作家”
"Ah! She is a writer."
你为什么这么想？
What made you think so?
是的 我认识许多作家
Yes, I know many writers.
在柏林 我是...我是大学教授
In Berlin I was ... I was professor at the university.
在这 恐怕只是个卑微的家教
Here I am just a humble tutor, I'm afraid.
不 请坐
No. Please, sit down.
谢谢
Thank you.
你离家很远吗 马奇小姐？
You are far from home, Miss March?
你想念家人吗？
Do you miss your family?
哦 非常想
Oh, very much.
尤其是我的姐妹们 还有罗利
My sisters especially. And Laurie.
她是你的姐妹？
She is your sister?
不 他是个朋友
No, he's a friend.
你喜欢你的咖啡吗？
You like your coffee?
哦 这...只是有点浓 我喜欢
Oh, it's... just very strong. I like it.
你的书房令人印象深刻
You have quite a library.
你是从德国带来这所有的书吗？
Did you bring all these books from Germany?
少数是
A few of them.
我可以看吗？
May I?
当然
Of course.
大部份我舍不得此便留下
Most...most of these I could not bear to leave behind.
我卖掉所有家当 换取来此的旅费...
I sold everything that I own to get my passage to come here...
但我的书...绝不卖
but my books...never.
莎士比亚
Shakespeare.
有些书 好熟悉
Some books are so familiar.
阅读它们就像又回到家了
Reading them is like being home again.
你会回柏林吗 拜尔教授？
Will you be returning to Berlin, Professor Bhaer?
佛德瑞克 叫我佛德瑞克就行
Friedrich. Call me Friedrich.
佛德瑞克
Friedrich.
不 悲剧的是
No. Sadly,
哥德和席勒的故乡都...不复存在了
the fatherland of Goethe and Schiller...is no more.
我崇拜哥德
I adore Goethe.
小时候 父亲为我念各种德国诗
My father used to read me all the German poets when I was a child.
真的？真令人惊讶
Really? That is most surprising.
这个 我的父母属于很不寻常的那部分康柯德人
Well, my mother and father were part of...a rather unusual circlein Concord.
你知道“超越论者”这个词吗？
Do you know the word "transcendentalist"?
这可是德国浪漫主义哲学
But this is German romantic philosophy.
我们抛开我们所有的束缚
We throw off all our constraints
并且通过洞察力和经验…开始了解自己
and we come to know ourselves...through insight and experience.
现在它已经过时了
It got out of fashion now.
恐怕 在马屈家还没有
Not in the March family, I'm afraid.
只不过所有的超越论...都在强调让自我完美
It's just that with all of this transcendence ... comes much emphasis on perfecting oneself.
所以这给你带来了不少麻烦吗？
This gives you a problem?
我是个无可救药的完美主义者
I'm hopelessly flawed.
要是我们能...
If only we could...
超越自我而不求完美
transcend ourselves without perfection.
像你们的诗人 沃尔特·惠特曼...整天来去于百老汇的街道...
Like your poet, Walt Whitman...who rides up and down the streets of Broadway all day...
对着怒吼的车潮咆哮出诗篇
shouting poetry against the roar of the carts.
“留下你寂静的森林 哦 自然...
" Keep your silent woods, O Nature...
“留下你河流旁寂静的天地” “留下你森林旁寂静的天地”
"And your quiet places by the river” “And your quiet places by the woods”
“森林旁”
“by the woods.”
“还我宁静的曼哈坦街道”
Give me the streets of Manhattan."
我想我们都是无可救药的完美主义者
I think we are all hopelessly flawed.
他穷的就像我想像中云游四海的哲学家
He is as poor as one might imagine an itinerant philosopher to be.
然而 几个星期过去
Yet, as the weeks go by,
我发现他对所有住在这里的人都很慷慨
that he is unfailingly generous...to all of us who live in the house.
我感谢能有一个朋友
I am grateful to have a friend.
这可是我们国家建立的基础
It is the system our nation was founded on.
而看看现在 它除了背叛了我们国家的理想之外还有什么
Come now. It was nothing short of a betrayal of our country's ideals.
我们国家的理想？
Our country's ideals?
一部宪法...一部否认公民基本权利...
A constitution...that denies the basic rights of citizenship...
否认女人和黑人权利的宪法 还能称之为宪法吗？
（指美国宪法最初规定妇女和黑人不具有投票权）
to women and black people?
他们刚通过第15条修正案 雅各布 他们可以投票了
They just passed the 15th Amendment, Jacob. They can vote.
是黑人男性可投票 查尔斯
Black men can vote, Charles.
如果一个女士有了丈夫 那她就不需要投票了
A lady has no need of suffrage if she has a husband.
-不 不 -你不喝酒吗？
-No, no. -You don't take wine?
我只喝药酒
Only medicinally.
那就假装你感冒了
Pretend that you've got a cold.
我同意 但女人既然作为一种道德力量...
I agree, but if women are a moral force...
难道她们就不该有权行政 布道 以及在法庭作证吗？
shouldn't they have the right to govern and preach and testify in court?
你想说什么 马屈小姐？
What is it, Miss March?
我觉得这是个很糟糕的逻辑：因为女人善良...
I find it poor logic to say that because women are good...
所以女人应该拥有投票权
women should vote.
男人可不是因为善良才可以投票 他们能投票是因为他们是男性
Men do not vote because they are good. They vote because they are male.
女人应该拥有投票权 不是因为她们是天使而男人是野兽...
And women should vote not because they are angels and men are animals...
而是因为我们都是人
but because we are human beings
并且我们都是这个国家的公民
and citizens of this country.
你该从事律师的 马屈小姐
You should have been a lawyer, Miss March.
我该从事许多职业的 梅耶先生
I should have been a great many things, Mr. Mayer.
佛德瑞克
Friedrich.
哦 我很抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
不 不 请进
No, please. Please, come in.
我有好消息
I have some good news.
报纸登了我两篇故事
A newspaper has published two of my stories,
而且希望看见更多作品
and they wish to see more.
太好了
This is wonderful.
就在这儿
Right there.
火山日报
- The Daily Volcano?
“罪人之尸”...
"The Sinner's Corpse"...
作者乔瑟芬·马屈
by Joseph March.
疯子 吸血鬼
Lunatics. Vampires.
你对这感兴趣？
This interests you?
人们喜欢惊悚小说 佛德瑞克
People like thrilling stories, Friedrich.
这是报纸所要的
This is what the newspapers want.
是 我想 我想这是事实
Yes. Yes, I suppose. I suppose that is true.
这钱能为贝丝买件新外套 我相信她会很高兴的
It will buy a new coat for Beth, and I'm sure she'll be grateful to have it.
乔
Joe.
我...
I...
我并不是想说教
I do not want to be your teacher.
不 请理解我
No, understand me.
我只是说你应该取悦的是自己
I am saying only that you should please yourself.
我的意见并不重要
My opinion is of no importance.
原谅我？
Do you forgive me?
当然
Of course.
我有一个礼物 一个经验
Then I make a gift. An experience.
你喜欢歌剧吗？
Do you like the opera?
哦 我喜欢！我是说 我想我喜欢
Oh, I do.I mean, I think I do.
在康科德我们貌似很少听到歌剧
We don't seem to get a lot of opera in Concord.
我没有看歌剧的衣服
I don't have an opera dress.
你会很美的
You will be perfect.
我们坐的地方 不必太...正式
Where we are sitting, we shall not be so...formal.
蕾拉是个女神
Leila is a goddess.
她立誓永不陷入爱河
She has made a promise never to love.
她若违背誓言 她将失去一切
If she breaks her vow, all will be lost.
哦 看 麻烦来了
Oh, look. Trouble is coming.
会发生什么事？
What's going to happen?
无可避免的命运
The inevitable.
蕾拉的灵魂觉醒了
Leila's soul is opening.
她陷入一个念头
She's drawn to an idea.
他说 “爱是致命的力量”
He says, " Love has a fatal power."
“你的心...明白我的心”
“Your heart...understood mine.”
“在愉快夜晚的深邃处...”
“In the depth of the fragrant night...”
“用我陶醉的灵魂倾听...”
“I listened with ravished soul...”
“你爱的声音”
“to your beloved voice.”
“你的心明白我的心”
“Your heart understood mine.”
哦 罗利！你这坏蛋！
Oh, Laurie! You wicked!
我们听说你在希腊还是哪里
We heard you were in Greece or somewhere.
罗利！快来！快来！
Laurie! Come! Come!
你一定是忙于事业吧 我想
You've been much occupied with business, I am sure.
我现在没有从事生意
I'm not pursuing business just now.
祖父同意我潜心音乐一阵子
Grandfather agreed I should concentrate...on my music for a while.
你认识弗雷德·沃恩吧？
You know Fred Vaughan?
你好 罗伦斯
Good day, Laurence.
是的 我看你对艺术很热衷 弗雷迪
（弗雷迪，弗雷德的昵称）
Yes. I see you've taken up a passion for art, Freddy.
马奇姑婆 您看来好极了
Aunt March, you look splendid.
我无法对你这么说 孩子
I cannot say the same for you, my boy.
亲爱的艾米 还要很久吗？我得睡了
Amy dear. Will you be long? I must retire.
是的 马屈姑婆
Yes, Aunt March.
希望你来看我们
Do come see us.
他们订婚了？
Are they engaged?
现在还没有
Not yet.
跳 跳 一 二 三 四
Hop, hop. One, two, three, four.
跳 跳 跳 转
Hop, hop, hop, turn.
佛德瑞克 镇定剂在白兰地里要多久溶解？
Friedrich, how long would it take strychnine to dissolve in brandy?
哦 大约八分钟？
Oh. About eight minutes?
挂腰上的是短剑 还是军刀？
And is a dagger worn at the waist, or is that a saber?
我想在这些小说里...短剑经常藏在靴里...
I think that in these novels...the dagger is usually concealed in the boot...
藏在那有黑鬓的男士身上
by a man with a dark moustache.
往这边走
Go this way.
快！快！
Hurry! Hurry!
哦 罗利 真可爱
Oh, Laurie, how lovely.
它本不是这样的 但
It isn't what it should be, but ...
你将它变美了
you have improved it.
请别这样
Please don't.
我比较喜欢以前率直和自然时的你
I liked you much better when you were blunt and natural.
我并没因此得到好处
It did not serve me well.
我发觉你变了
I find you changed.
事实上 我瞧不起你
In fact, I despise you.
你无所事事 花家里的钱 追求女人
You laze about spending your family's money and courting women.
你并不是真心喜爱音乐
You aren't serious about music.
我的作曲就像你的绘画
My compositions are like your paintings:
抄袭别人天赋的二流作品
mediocre copies of another man's genius.
你何不去伦敦找你祖父 做个有用的人
Then why don't you go to Grandfather in London and make yourself useful?
我应该这样的 但你为什么来不纠正我？
I should. Why don't you reform me?
我有个更实际的人
I've someone more practical in mind.
你并不爱弗雷德·沃恩
You do not love Fred Vaughan.
弗雷德·沃恩稳重又有礼...
Fred Vaughan is stable and well-mannered...
而且年收入四万
And has 40,000 a year.
我一直都知道我是不会嫁给穷人的
I've always known I would not marry a pauper.
我随时期待有人向我求婚
I expect a proposal any day.
你会后悔的
You'll regret it.
我会后悔的
I'll regret it.
我想起一个承诺
I'm reminded of a promise.
我是不是说过要在你死前吻你？
Didn't I say I would kiss you before you die?
你有乔的消息吗？
Do you hear from Jo?
她和一位德国教授做了朋友
She has befriended a German professor.
没错 毫无疑问他正在教她...体验人生
Yes. No doubt he's showing her...the ways of the world.
我不希望一个还爱着我姐姐的人来追求我!
I do not wish to be courted by someone who is still in love with my sister!
我没有爱上乔
I'm not in love with Jo.
那你怎么解释你的嫉妒呢?
Then how do you explain your jealousy?
我羡慕她的幸福
I envy her happiness.
我羡慕他的幸福
I envy his happiness.
我羡慕约翰·布鲁克能娶梅格
I envy John Brooke for marrying Meg.
我讨厌弗雷德·沃恩
I hate Fred Vaughan.
如果贝丝有爱人 我也会讨厌他的
If Beth had a lover, I would despise him too.
如同你一直知道 你不会嫁穷人...
Just as you have always known you would never marry a pauper...
我则一直知道...
I have always known...
我一定会成为马屈家的一员
I should be part of the March family.
我不想因为我的家族而被爱
I do not wish to be loved for my family.
就如同弗雷德也不想因为他年收入四万而被爱一样
Any more than Fred Vaughan wishes to be loved for his 40,000 a year.
小姐
Mademoiselle.
谢谢
Mercy.
我亲爱的艾米
My darling Amy.
我要的是你 不是你的家族
It is you I want and not your family.
我已前往伦敦 好让自己值得你尊敬
I've gone to London to make myself worthy of you.
请别做出我们彼此会后悔的事
Please, do not do anything we shall regret.
法门先生来访 小姐 我可以请他进来吗？
Monsieur Vaughan, mademoiselle. May I show him in?
佛德瑞克 你读了吗？
Friedrich, did you read it?
读过了 写得很好 乔
Yes. It's well written, Jo.
第一本小说 真是一项伟大的成就
And the first novel. What a great accomplishment.
今天我要拿给你朋友出版商菲尔斯看
I'm going to be showing it to your publisher friend, Mr. Fields, today.
他喜欢“罪人之尸”
He liked "The Sinner's Corpse."
怎么了？
What is it?
菲尔斯先生人很好 他会给你最忠实的意见
Mr. Fields is a good man. He will give you an honest opinion.
哦 我明白了
Oh, I see.
那你的忠实意见呢？
What is your honest opinion?
我是个哲学教授
I'm a professor of philosophy.
不 我想知道你的看法
No, I'd like to know what you think.
你应该写你的生活...
You should be writing from life...
写出自灵魂深处的东西
from the depths of your soul.
你现在的作品没有那个我有幸了解的女人的任何东西
There is nothing in here of the woman that I am privileged to know.
佛德瑞克 这就是我写的
Friedrich, this is what I write.
我道歉 如果这无法达到你的高水准
My apologies if it fails to live up to your high standards.
乔 你可以写的比这更好的...
Jo, there is more to you than this...
如果你有勇气去写
if you have the courage to write it.
梅格
Meg.
乔
Jo.
你为什么没告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
这种事很难开口嘛
One hardly speaks of such things.
哦 太好了
Oh, how wonderful.
贝丝好吗？
How is Beth?
你会发现她变了很多
You will find her much altered.
妈咪
Marmee.
她不让我们早点叫你回来
She wouldn't let us send for you sooner.
医生来过好几次...
The doctor has been here a number of times...
但是我们都无能为力了 我想...
but it's beyond all of us, and I think...
我想她在等着你...
I think she's been waiting for you...
贝丝...你得这些好喝的清汤全喝完
Beth...you're going to drink up all of this good broth.
我很高兴你回家了
I'm glad you're home.
我也是
So am I.
“皮威克先生脸色一变
" Mr. Pickwick changed color.
‘啊’ 瓦妥先生说
'Ah,' said Mr. Wartle.
“嗯 这很重要 我想 那就没什么可疑的了”
'Well, that's important. There's nothing suspicious then, I suppose."'
你在身边让我感觉更健康了
I feel stronger with you close by.
我会让你好起来的
I'm going to get you better yet.
如果上帝要我跟他走 没人阻挡得了他
If God wants me with Him, there is none who will stop Him.
我不在意
I don't mind.
我从来不像你们...
I was never like the rest of you...
为重要的事做计划
making plans about the great things I'd do.
我从来没有把自己看成什么了不起的人
I never saw myself as anything much.
没想过要像你一样成为大作家
Not a great writer like you.
贝丝 我不是什么大作家
Beth, I'm not a great writer.
但你将来会是
But you will be.
哦 乔 我好想念你
Oh, Jo, I've missed you so.
为什么每个人都想离开？
Why does everyone want to go away?
我喜欢待在家
I love being home.
可我不喜欢被抛下
But I don't like being left behind.
现在我是那个先走的人了
Now I am the one going ahead.
我并不害怕
I am not afraid.
我可以像你一样勇敢
I can be brave like you.
但我知道我会为了你得思乡病...即使我在天堂
But I know I shall be homesick for you...even in heaven.
不
No.
我不让你走
I won't let you go.
哦 我的乔
Oh, my Jo.
马屈姑婆卧病不起 无法承受海上旅行
Aunt March is bedridden and would not survive a sea voyage.
艾米必须等着 过一段时间才能回来
Amy must bide her time and return later.
这样也好
It's just as well.
我们会不会永远无法再团聚了？
Will we never all be together again?
早晨愉快
Lovely morning.
谢谢你 先生
Thank you, sir.
最亲爱的罗利
Dearest Laurie:
你可能还不知道关于贝丝的坏消息...
You may not have heard our sad news of Beth's...
“梅格已分娩了...
" Meg has entered her confinement...
可怜的艾米必须和马屈姑婆待在米维”
and poor Amy must stay in Vevey with Aunt March."
这是一个人无法承受的巨大悲痛
This is far too great a sorrow to bear alone.
请回来找我们 亲爱的泰迪
Please come home to us, Teddy dear.
你的 忠实的乔
Your faithful, Jo.
哦 罗利
Oh, Laurie.
我就知道你会来的
I knew you would come.
贝丝
钢琴的美丽浮现在贝丝快乐的脸庞...
The real charm of it lay in Beth's happy face ...
当她靠在崭新的钢琴上...钟爱地触动美丽的黑白琴键
as she leaned over the new piano and lovingly ouched ... the beautiful black and white keys.
接下来几分钟里 谣言四起...
During the next few minutes, the rumor circulated ...
说艾米·马屈有24个可口的莱姆果
that Amy March had got 24 delicious limes.
我跟你说过是她们替我打扮的 但我没说她们又是上粉又是束腰
I told you they dressed me up, but I didn't tell you that they powdered and squeezed
使我看来像是个时髦人物
and made me look a fashion plate.
说完 乔拿下她的帽子
As she spoke, Jo took off her bonnet.
四周一片大叫声 因为她茂密的秀发被剪短了
A general outcry arose, for all her abundant hair was cut short.
乔 你怎么可以？你可是个美人
Jo, how could you? You're one beauty.
什么都不会改变的 乔
Nothing's going to change, Jo.
为了大地的美丽 为了上天的荣耀
For the beauty of the earth，For the glory of the skies
为了我们与生俱来的爱 我们躺在四周
For the love which from our birth. Over and around us lies
万物之主 我们向您致敬
Lord of all to Thee we raise. This our hymn of grateful praise
“乔·马屈的小说”
"Jo March's novel."
大惊喜！
Surprise!
约翰 你有女儿了
John, you have a daughter.
还有一个儿子
And a son.
哦 妈咪 我无法相信你生了四次
Oh, Marmee, I can't believe you did this four times.
是这样 但可从没有一次生两个 亲爱的
Yes, but never two at once, my darling.
哦 黛西
Oh, Daisy.
哦 梅格 她真好看
Oh, Meg, she's so beautiful.
而他
And him.
他很英俊 他长大后会像他爸爸
He is handsome. He's going to look just like his papa when he grows up.
是的 他确实像约翰
Yes, he does look like John.
你有那位教授的消息吗？
Have you heard from the professor?
没有
No.
我们分手得并不愉快
We did not part well.
约翰和我也不总是意见一致 但我们之后都会解决的
John and I don't always agree, but then we mend it.
那会是谁？
Who could that be?
乔
Jo.
哦 泰迪 太神奇了！
Oh, Teddy, this is magic!
你简直是...
You are absolutely...
裹在面粉里！
Covered in flour!
哦 亲爱的！快进来
Oh, dear! Come in.
不 乔 再等一下
No, Jo, not yet.
我可以单独和你谈一下吗？
May I tell you something without the others?
你是我最亲爱的朋友
You're my dear friend.
我很高兴你第一个知道
I'm glad that you shall be the first to know.
请让我介绍...
May I present...
我妻子
my wife.
乔
Jo.
艾米
Amy.
哦 天啊！
Oh, my!
-送你的花 -谢谢你。
-Here, flowers. - Thank you.
快进来！
Come in!
毛织花边！哦！
Brussels lace! Oh!
我前往欧洲画主教堂...
I went to Europe to paint the great cathedrals...
但我无法忘怀我们家
but I couldn't get our home out of my mind.
噢 看艾米是怎么捕捉果树园的风景的
Oh, look how Amy has captured Orchard House.
漂亮
Lovely.
哦 真美丽
Oh, it's beautiful.
没有我想的那么漂亮
Not as beautiful as I wanted,
不过我还在学习
but I am still learning.
亲爱的小天使
Dear little angel.
乔 你得告诉我 身为姐妹...
Jo, you must tell me the truth, as a sister...
这关系强过婚姻
which is a relation stronger than marriage.
你一点都不在意吗？
Do you mind at all?
哦 不！
Oh, no.
我很惊讶
I was surprised.
要知道 我有可靠证据证明我们的泰迪…永远不会爱上别人
Mind you, I had it on good authority that our Teddy...would never love another.
而如今他却结婚了
And now he's gone and gotten married.
很高兴再听见你叫我泰迪
It's good to hear you call me Teddy again.
最后 我们都是一家人 我们应该一直都是这样
At last, we're all family, as we always should have been.
你得答应我会一直住在附近
You must promise me that you will always live close by.
我不能再失去一个妹妹了
I couldn't bear losing another sister.
乔 天气又阴又冷
Jo, it's so gloomy and chilly.
光是给这个地方取暖的煤就需要一大笔收入
One would require an income just for the coal to heat this place.
这亲爱的老姑娘到底在想什么呢?
What could the dear old girl have been thinking?
她很可能是同情我
Most likely she felt sorry for me.
这无家可归的老处女!
Decrepit homeless spinster!
哦 可怜的姑婆
Oh, poor Aunt.
这些年独自住在这
Living here all those years alone
无用的老房子里
in this useless old house.
没错 她的福气成为负担了 因为没人能分享
Yes, her blessings became a burden because she couldn't share them.
这不是一所很棒的学校吗?
Wouldn't this have made a wonderful school?
一所学校
A school.
这会是多大的挑战啊
What a challenge that would be.
哈啰 塔比 哈啰
Hello, Tuppy. Hello.
好孩子
Good boy.
佛德瑞克·贝尔教授 威佛利路 11号
“《小妇人》 乔·马屈著”
我的书！
My book!
有人出版了我的书
Someone's publishing my book.
有人出版了我的书！
Someone's publishing my book!
上帝帮忙！
Heaven help us!
来时没有信 它是怎么送到的？
It came with no letter. How did it arrive?
一个外国绅士拿来的 很奇怪的名字
Foreign gentleman brought it. Strange kind of name.
想不起来了 哦 他叫 福克斯 还是贝儿什么的
Can't think of it. Oh, Fox, or Bear or such.
是拜尔！ 你有让他等一下吗？
Bhaer! Did you ask him to wait?
我还以为他是某个带着结婚礼物的艾米小姐的欧洲朋友
I thought he was one of Miss Amy's European friends coming with a wedding gift.
我说 “马屈小姐和罗利先生住在隔壁”
I said, " Miss March and Mr. Laurie are living next door."
汉娜 你不会吧！
Hannah, you didn't!
然后他说他要赶火车
Then he said he had a train to catch.
佛德瑞克！
Friedrich!
哦 佛德瑞克 谢谢你带来我的书
Oh, Friedrich, thank you for my book.
当我没有你消息的时候...
When I didn't hear from you...
我以为你讨厌这本书
I thought you hated it.
哦 不
Oh, no.
读你的书就像打开一扇进入你心房的窗
Reading your book was like opening a window into your heart.
詹姆斯·菲尔斯从我手中取走 就不愿还给我了
James Fields took it out of my hands, and he would not give it back to me.
我说“这种消息我得亲自告诉她”
I said, "Such news I have to give to her myself."
这个 这是个愚蠢的冲动
Well, it was a silly impulse.
不 不 一点也不愚蠢
No, not silly at all.
很高兴见到你
It's so good to see you.
来见见我的家人
Come and meet my family.
不 我...
No, I...
谢谢 不过...
Thank you, but...
我得赶火车了
I have to catch a train.
我要到西部去
I am going to the West.
我的船明早由波士顿启航
My ship leaves from Boston tomorrow morning.
是的 西部的学校都很新
Yes, the schools in the West are young.
他们需要教授 而且...
They need professors and...
他们不那么在乎口音
they are not so concerned about the accent.
我也不在意
I don't mind it either.
你知道 我的姑婆把果树园留给我了
See, my aunt left me Plumfield.
它不是个果园 它是栋房子 事实上
It isn't a field. It's a house, actually.
一个相当大的房子
A rather large house.
除了拿来当学校什么也不适合...
And it isn't really good for anything except a school...
我要一所好学校...
and I want a good school...
一个对任何想学习的人都开放的地方 还有…
one that would be open to anyone who wanted to learn, and, well...
我需要一位懂得教学的人
I'll be needing someone who knows how to teach.
我能说什么让你留在这里吗?
Is there nothing I might say to keep you here?
我承认我期盼有个理由能留下来 但是...
I confess that I was hoping that I might have a reason to stay, but...
恭喜你的结婚庆典
congratulations on the celebration of your marriage.
哦 不！不 那是艾米
Oh, no! No, that's Amy.
那是我妹妹 艾米和罗利 实际上
That's my sister. Amy and Laurie, actually.
不 我还没结婚
No, I'm not married.
请不要离开
Please don't go so far away.
乔
Jo.
如此平凡的名字...却配给了这样不平凡的一个人
Such a little name for...for such a person.
你愿意拥有我吗？
Will you have me?
全心全意！
With all of my heart!
但我没有什么可以给你 我两手空空
But I have nothing to give you. My hands are empty.
现在不空了
Not empty now.